<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 17:55:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk at Technology Institute of Celaya</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/itc-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 17:55:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/itc-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last 9th of December I gave a talk at the Technology Institute of Celaya (Instituto Tecnológico de Celaya).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very important for me because this was the university where I graduated in 2005 as an engineer in electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My talk was part of a series of presentations related to research topics. In my case, even though I have done a lot of research, I choose not to focus on that. Instead, what I prepared was a smörgåsbord (to use a Swedish word) of cool stuff where I tried to catch the attention of the students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first suggestion I received was to change the name of the presentation; I decided to keep the original title: &amp;ldquo;A life voiding warranties&amp;rdquo; or in Spanish &amp;ldquo;Una vida invalidando garantías&amp;rdquo;. This was funny for me because the name does describe my life: for every electronic product I got I felt the need to open it to see what&amp;rsquo;s inside.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/itc2.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the first part of my presentation I focused on my professional life: the project that I have developed over the years and my current tasks. In the second part I presented my &lt;a href=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/projects/&#34;&gt;free-time projects&lt;/a&gt; and my experiences from working in hacker-spaces, mainly in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hackafe.org/events.html&#34;&gt;Hackafe Plovdiv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my presentation with a few tips that I think, personally, that have helped me during my life. Let me share some of the tips with you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be naive&lt;/em&gt; : when solving a problem, before thinking too much about it, try to come up with a naive solution. Thinking too much about the purpose of what I develop, stops me from doing new things&amp;hellip; because I start finding reasons not to do it. One of the biggest examples were my beginnings with Functional Programming. Out of curiosity I started to learn it, and it&amp;rsquo;s what have had the strongest impact in my professional life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep yourself up-to-date&lt;/em&gt; : this is one of the most difficult things to do because nowadays there are tons of information on the web. I try to dig into many topics: different technologies, science, arts, design and psychology. Extrapolating ideas is easier when you get to know various ways of thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share&lt;/em&gt; : During my student life I have met many people who think that keeping their knowledge in a sealed box will make them better than the other. On the contrary, for me, sharing my knowledge has always been a way to learn things better. That&amp;rsquo;s why I helped my classmates when studying for exams; teaching is the best way of learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vult at OpenFest Bulgaria</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/openfest-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 17:17:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/openfest-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last november I attended to the OpenFest 2016 in Bulgaria where I presented an overview of Vult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenFest is the biggest conference in Bulgaria focused on open technologies. The conference is held in Sofia. This is the second time I attend but the first time presenting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the complete video of my presentation here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;415&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_UQ0tUK2SQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the demos that I showed there. I also prepared a version of the closing song where I explain with more detail what happens in the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;415&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_qmTbsk5TA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the code, models and patches in the following repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/modlfo/vult-examples&#34;&gt;Vult Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art &amp; Tech Meetup</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/art-tech-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 17:55:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/art-tech-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last 20 of October we organized the first Art &amp;amp; Tech Meetup at Hackafe Plovdiv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/art&amp;#43;tech.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this meet up is bringing people together for an eclectic range of ideas related to music, visuals or any artistic manifestation of technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This meet up consist on a set of short presentations by the attendees in order to get immersed in the creativity of others. The presentations can be improvised or prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you talk about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interesting projects that you have made,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideas that can be further developed by the group,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;presentations on the new developments on tools for making digital art,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tutorials on interesting tools,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;live performances or demonstrations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had very interesting presentations. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introduction to VR - basic principles and creation of content&amp;rdquo; - Atanas Dinchev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Voice effects&amp;rdquo; - Todor Arnaudov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Audio synthesis everywhere&amp;rdquo; - Leonardo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The perception of ancient cultural heritage nowadays. A walk-through the interactive installation Plovdiv Timeline&amp;rdquo; - Petko Tanchev&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Media and architecture projects&amp;rdquo; - Moritz Behrens  and Nina Valkanova&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/art&amp;#43;tech-pic1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/art&amp;#43;tech-pic2.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Media Workshop</title>
      <link>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/creative-media-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 18:28:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/blog/creative-media-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Creative Media Workshop was a kind of Hackathon led by Barak Koren and Petko Tanchev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/creative-media-workshop.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I applied for the event and was accepted. During the event, &lt;a href=&#34;https://barakooda3d.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;Barak Koren&lt;/a&gt; gave us an introduction to the software called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.derivative.ca&#34;&gt;TouchDesigner&lt;/a&gt; which is used to do real-time video generation and processing. After the introduction to the software we had one and a half day to come up with an idea and complete a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been a &amp;ldquo;audio&amp;rdquo; guy, but for the first time I had the opportunity to explore video generation. I had a clear idea about what I wanted to do, and teamed up with Ivona Ivanova who helped me develop the visuals. The project we developed was called &amp;ldquo;Visceral Dance&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;center-figure&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://replace-this-with-your-hugo-site.com/images/visceral-dance.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bAnOoREr0vo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was selected to be part of the exhibition at the Night of the Museums and Galleries in Plovdiv. You can read more about the event in &lt;a href=&#34;https://petkotanchev.wordpress.com/2016/11/20/creative-media-lab-of-plovdiv/&#34;&gt;Petko Tanchev&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://barakooda3d.wordpress.com/2016/10/03/plovdiv-media-workshop/&#34;&gt;Barak Koren&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>